

#### RESEARCHER, TOYOTA CENTRAL R&D LABS., INC.

41-1, Yokomichi, Nagakute, Aichi 480-1192, Japan

【 (+81) 90-7741-8679 | ■ d.inoue.jp@gmail.com | ★ https://inody.github.io

### About me

Daisuke Inoue is a researcher at Toyota Central R&D Labs,. Inc. He received a B.E. degree in engineering from Osaka University in 2014 and an M.S. degree in informatics from Kyoto University in 2017. He received a Ph.D. degree in mathematical science from the University of Tokyo in 2024. His current research interests include control engineering, multi-agent systems, and swarm intelligence.

## **Experience**

Toyota Central R&D Labs., Inc.

Aichi, Japan

RESEARCH ENGINEER

Aug. 2017 - Present

• Controller design for very large-scale systems

· Exploring applications of quantum annealing machines for control engineering

Kyoto University Kyoto, Japan

Teaching Assistant

July. 2016 - Mar. 2017

• Teaching Assistant of Complex Analysis Class

Siemens Industry Software N.V.

Leuven, Belgium

RESEARCH INTERNSHIP

July. 2015 - Mar. 2016

• Motion Controller Design for Airbus A330 based on 1-D & 3-D Co-simulation

Mitsubishi Heavy Industries, Ltd.

Kobe, Japan

INTERNSHIP

July. 2014

• Development of Nuclear Power Plant Simulator

## **Education**

The University of Tokyo

Tokyo, Japan

PH.D STUDENT

Mar. 2024

• Thesis: Numerical Methods for Nonlinear Partial Differential Equations Arising from Large-Scale Multi-Agent Control Problems

**Kyoto University** 

Kyoto, Japan

M.S. IN INFORMATICS

Mar. 2017

• Thesis: Stability Analysis of Networked Monotone Systems

Osaka University

Osaka, Japan

B.S. IN ENGINEERING

Mar. 2014

• Thesis: Stationary performance evaluation of control systems with random dither quantization

## **Selected Publication**

JOURNAL (REFEREED)

# Partially Centralized Model-Predictive Mean Field Games for Controlling Multi-Agent Systems

IFAC Journal of Systems and Control

D. Inoue, Y. Ito, T. Kashiwabara, N. Saito, and H. Yoshida

2023

### A fictitious-play finite-difference method for linearly solvable mean field games

ESAIM: M2AN

D. Inoue, Y. Ito, T. Kashiwabara, N. Saito, and H. Yoshida

2023

### Traffic Signal Optimization on a Square Lattice with Quantum Annealing

Scientific Reports

D. Inoue, A. Okada, T, Matsumori, K. Aihara and H. Yoshida

2021

Optimal Transport-based Coverage Control for Swarm Robot Systems: Generalization of the Voronoi Tessellation-based Method

IEEE Control Systems Letters

D. INOUE, Y. ITO AND H. YOSHIDA

Model Predictive Control for Finite Input Systems using the D-Wave Quantum Annealer

Scientific Reports 2020

D. INOUE, H. YOSHIDA

Conference (Refereed)

Stability Analysis of Logit Dynamics with Committed Minority and Internal/External **Conformity Biases** 

Proc. 22nd IFAC World Congress

Yokohama, Japan, 2023

T. MIYANO, Y. ITO, D. INOUE, S. KOIDE, AND T. HATANAKA

D. Inoue, Y. Ito, T. Kashiwabara, N. Saito, and H. Yoshida

the Voronoi Tessellation-based Method

2021 IEEE International Conference Model Predictive Mean Field Games for Controlling Multi-Agent Systems on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics

Melbourne, Australia, 2021

Optimal Transport-based Coverage Control for Swarm Robot Systems: Generalization of

American Control Conference 2021

D. INOUE, Y. ITO AND H. YOSHIDA

New Orleans, USA, 2021

**Stochastic Self-Organizing Control for Swarm Robot Systems** 

ICSI 2019

D. INOUE, D. MURAI, AND H. YOSHIDA

Chiang Mai, Thailand, 2019

Distributed Range-based Localization for Swarm Robot Systems using Sensor-Fusion **Technique** 

SENSORNETS 2019

D. INOUE, D. MURAI, Y. IKUTA AND H. YOSHIDA

Prague, Czech Republic, 2020

Replay attack detection in control systems with quantized signals

European Control Conference 2015

K. KASHIMA AND D. INOUE

Linz, Austria, 2015

Stationary performance evaluation of control systems with random dither quantization European Control Conference 2014

K. KASHIMA AND D. INOUE

Strasbourg, France, 2014

### Awards

2016

2017 Repayment Exemption for Students with Excellent Grades, Japan Student Services Organization

Best presentation award on The 59th Japan Automatic Control Conference, The Society of Instrument

and Control Engineer

Research Encouragement Award on The 58nd Annual Conference of the Institute of Systems, Control 2015

and Information Engineers, The Institute of Systems, Control and Information Engineers

Research Encouragement Award on The 1st Multi-symposium on Control Systems, The Society of

Instrument and Control Engineers

## **Grants**

2014

Vulcanus in Europe (15,540 dollars), Selected students get to go to Europe to study the local language, and 2015 to have a working experience by EU-Japan Centre for Industrial Cooperation in Institute for International Studies and Training.